me@seanhelvey.com

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Full stack software engineer with experience in SAAS, e-commerce, AI, web, mobile, and cloud-based applications. Expertise in Python, Django, and Google Cloud Platform (GCP). Equipped with strong technical skills and demonstrated aptitude for composing practical code that works and integrates well with existing components. Good at solving hard problems.

Python HTML / CSS Docker
Django JavaScript Kubernetes

PostgreSQL jQuery Google Cloud Platform

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Python / Django Developer, Koinonia Family Services

March 2021 - Present

Remote

- Lead developer of application serving 1000s of foster care and adoption placements annually.
- Roughly 200,000 days of care provided through the use of this proprietary system per year.
- Increased test coverage 400% adding Continuous Integration and Deployment (CI/CD) through GitLab.
- Maintained complex Python, Django, Docker, Kubernetes infrastructure after losing lead developer.
- Created new fully managed serverless Google App Engine project with Python and Django.
- Introduced asynchronous Google Tasks for background processing improving user experience.
- Incorporated PostgreSQL full-text search and parsing of multiple file types including PDF.
- Wrote shell scripts using Bash to connect to Kubernetes instance, dump and download data.
- Expanded available gender roles in legacy platform through the database and user interface.

#### Owner, Lifework LLC

January 2020 - March 2021

Santa Barbara, CA

Affordable software development for non-profit causes, social enterprises, and community based organizations.

- Squarespace site for local Insight meditation group https://www.insightmeditationsb.org/
- Squarespace site for local Zen meditation group <a href="https://www.santabarbarazencenter.org/">https://www.santabarbarazencenter.org/</a>

## **Senior Software Engineer, Lull**

March 2020 - September 2020

Goleta, CA

Managed continuous updates and upgrades on Lull's e-commerce platform, including integration of payment providers—PayPal, Verifi, Braintree, Apple Pay—and development of novel components using Vue.js. Managed continuous integration with TeamCity. Developed A/B Testing with Google Optimize & Optimizely.

# Senior Software Engineer, AppFolio

April 2019 - January 2020

Goleta, CA

Created scalable, robust, and simple web-based software solutions for a leading property management SAAS company.

- Created visualizations for AppFolio's AI virtual leasing assistant.
- Integrated 3<sup>rd</sup>-party leasing provider, Blue Moon.
- Refactored sign-in application from 7 to 3 screens.
- Developed date/time component to automate scheduling.

## Lead Instructor, Galvanize

July 2017 - March 2019

Boulder, CO

LinkedIn: seanhelvey

Sean Helvey Page 2

Lead instructor for an immersive web development bootcamp. Prepared eight cohorts of twenty students to become full stack developers.

- "Campus Captain" for Galvanize Boulder.
- Expanded and taught curricula on JavaScript, React, Redux, and Cloud Native Essentials.

## **Software Engineer, Pearson**

November 2016 - July 2017

Boulder, CO

Built and maintained machine learning software to grade and report results for a leading testing company.

- Cut statistics processing time in half.
- Created dashboard visualizations displaying histograms used to train machine learning models.
- Developed numerous experiments using Jupyter/IPython notebooks and Docker containers.

# **Chief Technology Officer, Blue Hook**

May 2014 - November 2016

Boulder, CO

Founded and led an independent software development consulting firm.

- Designed and developed web-based contractor portal for construction and property management company, Motili.
- Led a team of expert coders on a satellite imagery search engine project for Apollo Mapping, including development of a full stack application to enable front-end search result filtering.
- Built and tested custom components and data visualizations for KPMG.
- Optimized web-based flight reservation system for Hawaiian Airlines for accessibility by visual and hearing impaired users.

## **Software Engineer, Simple Energy**

October 2013 - May 2014

Boulder, CO

Designed, built, and maintained web experiences to engage utility customers for a specialized SAAS company.

## **Software Engineer, Genscape**

November 2012 - June 2013

Boulder, CO

Developed and maintained data collection and analysis system for natural gas pipeline production and market analysis software company.

## **EDUCATION**

## Master of Science in Computer Science, New York University

2012

- Emphasis in Databases and Natural Language Processing.
- Financial Software Development Intern at Bloomberg.
- Capstone project Smart thermostat development at EnergyHub.

## Bachelor of Science in Business, Cal Poly San Luis Obispo

2006

- Concentration in Finance & Accounting.
- Fixed Income Research Intern at Allegiance Capital.
- Member of the Student Managed Portfolio Project.

## **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

Shine Ambassador, Yoga Soup	2020 - Present
Volunteer, Best Day Foundation	2019 - 2020
Coach, Techstars Startup Weekend	2019 - 2020
Champion, CoderDojo Boulder	2014 - 2015
Event Volunteer, Boulder County Independent Business Alliance	2014 - 2015

GitHub: seanhelvey